<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Esplanade Psychological Services</title>
    <link>https://yourbrain.doctor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Esplanade Psychological Services</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 21:43:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yourbrain.doctor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assessment</title>
      <link>https://yourbrain.doctor/assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 21:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yourbrain.doctor/assessment/</guid>
      <description>Neuropsychological Evaluation Neuropsychological assessment involves multiple methods of investigation and examines biological, psychological, and contextual factors in producing a comprehensive assessment of functioning. Testing usually includes review of medical or school records, clinical interview, and psychometric testing. It concludes with a feedback session during which we will discuss your results.
A neuropsychological evaluation is a test to measure how well a person&amp;rsquo;s brain is working. We use up-to-date, standard measures to develop a detailed profile of learning strengths and weaknesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapy</title>
      <link>https://yourbrain.doctor/therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 21:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yourbrain.doctor/therapy/</guid>
      <description>Approach I have an eclectic approach to therapy that is engaging and interactive. I have advanced training in Cognitive Behavioral Therapy, Mindfulness Techniques, and Dialectical Behavioral Therapy. I also have experience with Executive Functioning Training - including the Unstuck and On Target! cirriculum and cognitive remediation programs.
My theraputic approach is strength based, insight oriented skill building collaboration. I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to offer a free consultation to determine if I am the right therapist for your family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://yourbrain.doctor/whoweare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 21:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yourbrain.doctor/whoweare/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ailion provides private, discrete neuropsychological assessment and consultation services for children and adults. Dr. Alyssa Ailion is a licensed clinical psychologist and neuropsychologist with years of clinical experience — personally conducts all of the evaluations. My approach is warm, intellectually curious and collaborative, always keeping goals in mind and explaining the process along the way.
Dr. Ailion&amp;rsquo;s evaluations provide comprehensive examination of a broad range of learning disabilities, school difficulties, medical etiology, and emotional challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://yourbrain.doctor/faqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 21:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yourbrain.doctor/faqs/</guid>
      <description>What is your waitlist? We have immediate availability to provide parents and educators with strategies or steps to take at home or school.
Why has a neuropsychological assessment been requested? A neuropsychological assessment can be requested for a number of reasons including:
Diagnosis: Test results are sometimes used to help understand the cause of problems with your thinking and understanding. For example, test results might be used to determine if your child&amp;rsquo;s school difficulties are due to depression, anxiety, or an underlying learning or attention issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
